Soumaya Mahdi

Web Developer

I'm a hard-working web developer with an ability for creating elegant solutions in the least amount of time, a 1+ year of experience and a great passion for software engineering. Specialized in PHP, Google cloud platform, and MVC frameworks. Familiar with popular CMS like WordPress. Having a wide knowledge in JavaScript and MYSQL relational database management systems.

Address: Street 9 - Discovery Gardens - Dubai

Phone: +971 50 581 8406

Email: soumaya.mahdi95@gmail.com

LinkedIn: Soumaya Mahdi

SKILLS AND PROFICIENCIES

- HTML5, CSS3, MySQL, Bootstrap,
 Hypertext Preprocessor (PHP), JavaScript,
 ReactJS, Asynchronous JavaScript and
 XML (AJAX), jQuery, WordPress, Google
 Cloud Platform (GCP), SQL, GitHub,
 Model-View-Controller (MVC)
- Teamwork, multitasking, attention to detail, fast learning.
- Web development, front and back-end development.

LANGUAGES

- Arabic (Native)
- English: Professional working proficiency
- French (B1 Certificate): Limited working proficiency

WORK HISTORY

Freelanced Software Developer

SISERVS | Mar 2019 - Feb 2020

- Web design and development, social media and website content management.
- Develop user-centric solutions to increase the efficiency and client satisfaction.
- Client Relationship Management.
- Researches and develops new ways to improve development process.

PHP Developer Intern

CPAGrag | Jan 2018 - Jun 2018

- Reporting daily stats about projects and tasks.
- Maintaining servers, websites, and technical devices inside the office.
- Developing and designing landing pages, admin panels and blogs, managing the content of the landing pages.
- Developed, installed, and configured internal applications, as well as new application releases into test and production environments.
- Conceptualizing and developing a library for the company to reduce additional costs involved in using third-party libraries.
- Creating the web-based promotional collateral for different campaigns. Optimizing home and landing pages, also including the agency's own.
- Designing and developing email campaigns with PHP and JavaScript.

Electronic Engineer Intern

S. &A. S. Co.Ltd (Security & Automation Systems) | Apr 2016 - Jun 2016

Completed three-month undergraduate trainee program reporting to my college supervisor.

- Soldering components and repairing circuit boards.
- Monitoring the product line (SMD automatic assembly, reflow soldering, automatic optical inspection, wave soldering.)
- Software download, testing and troubleshooting.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Masters in Computer and Communication Engineering

Lebanese International University | 2018 - Present

Bachelor of Science in Computer and Communication Engineering

Lebanese University- Faculty of Technology | 2014 - 2018

LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS

freeCodeCamp certifications

- Front End Development Libraries | Jan 2022
- Responsive Web Design | Jan 2022

LinkedIn certifications

- Google Ads Essential Training | Nov 2021
- <u>SEO Foundations</u> | Nov 2021
- <u>SQL: Data Reporting and Analysis</u> | Nov 2021